STEPHEN BUSKIE

FINANCE | ENGINEERING | DATA

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Problem solver with world class engineering skillset. Experienced in influencing joint-ventures on billion dollar investments and c-suite executive reporting. Demonstrated ability to work effectively with multiple cultures through respect and communication while coordinating globally deployed teams for business planning purposes. Developer of digital solutions leveraging big data for global audiences.

- Houston, Texas | Internationally mobile stephenbuskie@gmail.com
 - https://sbuskie.github.io
- **(** +44 797 953 2368 | +1 832 616 7767

KEY SKILLS

- Management Information
- Leadership
- Business Intelligence
- Data Analytics and Visualisation
- Digital Twins
- Forecasting
- Stock Exchange Announcements
- Reporting and KPI Ownership
- Risk Management
- Scrum and Agile
- Investor Relations
- Coaching and Mentoring
- Finance and Audit
- Big Data

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Production Performance Lead, bp; Houston, US – Jan 2021 - Present

Squad lead for the production performance team, responsible for bp's external reporting of their global hydrocarbon production. This includes managing a multi-disciplinary team of 5 performance advisors and analysts in support of these demands. Accountabilities include:

- Single point of accountability for bp's quarterly production reporting to the market; includes inputs to bp's quarterly results announcements, stock exchange announcements, annual report and sustainability report.
- Executive reporting and performance management on a weekly, monthly and quarterly basis; Lead for executive production management information during Group Performance Reviews, Operational Performance Reviews and Monthly Production Reviews.
- Performance management and coordination of bp's business planning for the production domain. Liaising with teams across >15 geographies where bp operate, delivering value through consistency.

Performance Analyst, bp; Houston, US - 2019 -2021

Performance analyst responsible for the integrity, accuracy and timely delivery of management information related to bp's global Upstream hydrocarbon production (>2,500mboed). Highlights include:

- Development lead for digital business intelligence tools related to bp's production portfolio. Designed and deployed Microsoft Power BI reports globally facilitating improved business planning, quarterly variance commentary and executive weekly reporting.
- Production subject matter expert aligning bp's production management workflows with the reinvented ambition to be net zero by 2050 or sooner, advising bp's Strategy and Sustainability team. Led the development of carbon as a production stream with equal importance to oil and gas production. Elicited improved and simplified carbon forecasting globally.
- Collaborated with Palantir Technologies and bp data architects to connect SAP reported hydrocarbon production to the data lake, streamlining flow of carbon data to executive dashboards, quarterly external reports and bp's annual sustainability report.
- Owned investor relations supplemental information for quarterly CFO and CEO investor calls; a team member of the "panel of experts" providing realtime support to the executives during investor calls.
- Additional c-suite responsibilities included risk management and reporting coordinator for bp's Reservoir Development (subsurface) function and supporting bp's quarterly appraisal table, part of bp's ~\$12-16bn/year capital allocation process; delivered to the Upstream COO.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating Systems | Windows, UNIX, Linux
- Data Visualisation | Excel, PowerBl,
 Spotfire, Streamlit
- Scripting Languages | Python, Bash
- Time-series Forecasting
- Microsoft 0365
- Microsoft PowerApps
- Azure Dev Ops
- SAP
- Applied Engineering | PETEX, Kappa
- Simulation Modelling | Nexus

Reservoir Engineer, bp; Aberdeen, UK - 2013-2019

Managed complex reservoirs using both state of the art engineering practices (big data analytics, ensemble modelling and simulation modelling) and analytically from first principles. Applied pragmatic engineering practices to solve complex, multi-disciplinary, billion dollar problems. Experienced in all aspects of reservoir and petroleum engineering creating digital twins of physical assets, with highlights including:

- Achieved approval of a 10-year facility life extension of a giant North Sea oil field. Previous teams had unsuccessfully attempted to gain partner alignment for this project. Identified the triggers behind joint venture misalignment and constructed the project to resolve the issues. This added >80mmstb gross reserves and >\$350m NPV10 to the joint venture business in the reference case.
- Appraised the technical feasibility for power options for a future offshore fixed platform facility; gas from the basin using the existing gas export infrastructure or leveraging a future onshore 440MW, 103 turbine greenfield wind power development. This supported bp's aim to be net zero on a Scope 1 and 2 GHG emissions basis.
- Advised product development for bp's relationship with Palantir Technologies, working cross-functionally with Palantir engineers and data architects.
 Counseled on world class digital toolkits knitting together real-time sensor data, sparse data sets and simulation forecasts outputs to improve production operations.

EDUCATION

MSc Petroleum Engineering, Distinction; Imperial College London, UK 2012-2013

Graduated with distinction. Attained full corporate sponsorship covering academic fees and living stipend. Attained World Education Service (WES) degree equivalency for USA and Canada.

BEng (Hons) Mechanical Engineering, First Class; University of Strathclyde, UK 2008-2012

Runner-up of the European Science, Engineering and Technology (SET) awards, in the 'Best Mechanical Engineering Student' category as judged by the Institute of Mechanical Engineers. The SET Awards provide a showcase for educational excellence by publicly recognising the exceptional achievements of both students and universities. They are Europe's most high profile event for science, engineering and technology undergraduates.

Awarded the University of Strathclyde Institute of Mechanical Engineers individual project prize. Additionally awarded final year scholarship based on demonstrated academic record.